

Nadjib BENKHELLAT Software Engineering Manager/ Senior Developer

https://dz.linkedin.com/in/nadjib-benkhellat-7a794817/ (213) 552 115 201/ benkhellatnadjib@gmail.com

Summary: Strong objective focused personality. Have always been leading teams to many succeeded deliveries on various projects in multi-functional and distributed teams. Had a chance to gain early technical knowledge as a software developer and perfected management skills through leading teams on both technical aspect and organization. As a manager, always pushing teams to innovate within the best return on investment.

KEY SKILLS

SCRUM methodology
UP Methodology
Coding (Senior Level)
GPS software design (experienced)
Project management
Software design
Data Base design and implementation
Scientific analysis and research

KEY STRENGTH

Objective oriented
Team leading spirit
Very well organized
International teams experience
Scientific background
Technical and management
knowledge

AWARDS

Second place for my team in international competition for a contract with a big London company.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING/PROJECT MANAGER at

i2b/RedFabriq/IntelliX,

Algiers, from • June 2006 to present

Aptitude: Relentless problem solver; applying analytical, design, and technical skills. Effective, hands-on leader with proved success developing applications for large scale of domains: companies business management, GPS fleet management, very large distribution companies complete management,

Gained early experience in technical subject as senior software developer and growing on management skills through multiple experiences and well conducted project on an international level. With a scientific approach, very effective at managing complex research subjects and highly complex environments (critical deliveries and systems).

Leading Algerian / French Teams into delivering multiple projects involving large scale of technologies for a variety of European customers.

MAJOR ACHIEVEMENTS

- + Optimizing the software by analysis, correction, collecting feedback and adapting.
- + Leading the team to a win spirit.
- + Establishing process of communication and collaboration with other company services (sales, hardware department, operations department, ...)
- + Eliminated all major software and platform (infrastructure) troubles that blocked sales activity.
- + Introducing the software development team to the Unified Process Methodology
- + Succeeding to conduct Algerian teams as a project manager / scrum master into delivering high quality software (international standards) to European companies

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER at 12B

Algiers, from • December 2014 to present

In charge of the software engineering department. Leading cross-profile software team (software architect / developers, graphical designers, systems and network administrators...) into software production. Working with product owners, analysis, engineering, quality and operations profiles across internal and external teams.

Collaborating with engineers on technical lead matters and provide a technical lead on deliveries (by developing, executing and planning). Guiding the team into an iterative production process and establishing best practices (coding and management).

- + Realization of a GPS tracking web application (JAVA Technologies)
- + Realization of back end management software for GPS fleet administration activity (.Net Technologies)
- + Task force to establish development best practices
- + Transform the team spirit into an objective focused working way

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER at I2B

Algiers, from June 2014 to December 2014

Full Stack senior developer (UI, Business layer, Data layer, data base modeling, tests...).

- + Creating multiplatform mobile application based on web services (android, iOs, windows phone)
- + Part of a project team for the realization of wpf backend desktop application (for internal fleet management)
- + Requirements study and design documents production

PROJECT MANAGER / SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER at FreeLance

Algiers, from • 2012 – 2014

As an independent consultant, involved in many projects for variety of customers. Had a chance to work for government institutions (ministries).

- + Full stack development of a fishing data monitoring for the Ministry of Fisheries and Marine Resources (web application)
- + Full Stack development of centralized management system of all Ministry of Fisheries and Marine Resources managed institutes (web application using DevExpress XAF)
- + Full Stack development of a vehicles parts shop management (store, sells, ...)
- + Full stack development of web site for a private customer (using Joomla CMS)
- + Full stack development of gas filling station (desktop application)

PROJECT MANAGER at RedFabriq

Algiers, from • 2009 – 2011

Managing several teams of engineers in project for European customers (French and English). Applying SCRUM methodology as a managing methodology. Multiple projects scales and related fields: distribution, web site (jewelry), task tracking, marketing web site, ...

- + Scrum master in international competition of a contract with an important European customer (placed second)
- + Thesis coach for engineers end of studies project

Resume: Nadjib Benkhellat 2|Page

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER at IntelliX Networks

Algiers, from • 2006 – 2009

Full stack developer. Involved in all project steps: requirements definition, design, realization (coding), testing, deploying and accompanying customers in software use.

EDUCATION

COMPUTING ENGINEER at the National Institute of Computing Science, Algiers (2000-2005). Specialization: Computing Systems.

End of study thesis, "Image segmentation using, quantic genetic algorithms and ant colony optimization". Completed with excellent mention.

TRAINING

- "PROJECT MANAGEMENT AND MS PROJECT 2010", REDFABRIQ, 2010
- "C# PROGRAMMING ON VISUAL STUDIO 2008", INTELLIX, 2008
- "PROJECT MANAGEMENT USING SCRUM APPROACH", REDFABRIQ, 2009

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH, FRENCH (WITH DALF DIPLOMA), ARABIC AND KABYLE.

Resume: Nadjib Benkhellat 3 | P a g e